Guide to the Harvey Williams Cushing Papers in the Yale University Library
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Papers held in Manuscripts and Archives, Part I
  - Writings, 1902-1939; Series III; 11 linear feet (24 boxes, 8 reels)
    - Addresses, papers, and reports
      - The Presentation of the Henry Jacob Bigelow Medal (266), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 193, Reel 146)
      - Studies in Acromegaly VII (267), 1927 (Box 183, Folder 194, Reel 146)
      - Electro-surgery as an Aid to the Removal of Intracranial Tumors (269), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 195, Reel 146)
      - Electro-surgery as an Aid to the Removal of Intracranial Tumors (269), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 196, Reel 146)
      - Electro-surgery as an Aid to the Removal of Intracranial Tumors (269), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 197, Reel 146)
      - Angioblastic Meningiomas (270), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 198, Reel 146)
      - Meningiomas Arising from the Tuberculum Sellae (271), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 199, Reel 146)
      - Meningiomas Arising from the Tuberculum Sellae (271), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 200, Reel 147)
      - Meningiomas Arising from the Tuberculum Sellae (271), 1928 (Box 183, Folder 201, Reel 147)
      - Chronological List of Publications from the Surgical Department of the Peter Bent Brigham Hospital and the Laboratory of Surgical Research, Harvard Medical School (272), 1929 (Box 183, Folder 202, Reel 147)
      - Report of the Surgeon-in-Chief (273), 1929 (Box 183, Folder 203, Reel 147)
      - The Medical Career: An Address on "The Ideals, Opportunities, and Difficulties of the Medical Profession" (274), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 204, Reel 147)
      - Remarks at the Children's Hospital Campaign Dinner (275), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 205, Reel 147)
      - Exercises in Celebration of the Bicentenary of the Birth of John Hunter (277), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 206, Reel 147)
      - The Chiasmal Syndrome of Primary Optic Atrophy and Bitemporal Field Defects in Adult Patients with a Normal Sella Turcica (278), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 207, Reel 147)
      - The Chiasmal Syndrome of Primary Optic Atrophy and Bitemporal Field Defects in Adult Patients with a Normal Sella Turcica (278), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 208, Reel 147)
      - The Chiasmal Syndrome of Primary Optic Atrophy and Bitemporal Field Defects in Adult Patients with a Normal Sella Turcica (278), 1929 (Box 184, Folder 209, Reel 147)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Medulloblastomas (280), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 210, Reel 147)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Medulloblastomas (280), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 211, Reel 147)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Medulloblastomas (280), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 212, Reel 147)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Medulloblastomas (280), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 213, Reel 147)
      - Report of the Surgeon-in-Chief (282), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 214, Reel 147)
      - The Separate Growth-promoting and Gonad-stimulating Hormones of the Anterior Hypophysis (283), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 215, Reel 148)
      - The Separate Growth-promoting and Gonad-stimulating Hormones of the Anterior Hypophysis (283), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 216, Reel 148)
      - Studies in the Physiological Properties of the Growth-promoting Extract of the Anterior Hypophysis (285), 1930 (Box 184, Folder 217, Reel 148)
      - An American Tribute to Sir Anthony Bowlby (286), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 218, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 219, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 220, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 221, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 222, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 223, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 224, Reel 148)
      - Experiences with the Cerebellar Astrocytomas (289), 1930 (Box 185, Folder 225, Reel 148)
      - Report of the Surgeon-in-Chief (290), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 226, Reel 148)
      - Eulogy of Major-General Clarence R. Edwards (291), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 227, Reel 148)
      - A Review of Homans' Textbook of Surgery (292), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 228, Reel 148)
      - Acknowledging Reprints (293), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 229, Reel 148)
      - Welch Lecture (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 230, Reel 148)
      - I. The Reaction to Posterior Pitutary Extract (Pituitrin) when Introduced into the Cerebral Ventricles (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 231, Reel 148)
      - II. The Similarity in the Responses to Posterior Lobe Extract (Pituitrin) and to Pilocarpine when Injected into the Cerebral Ventricles (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 232, Reel 148)
      - III. The Action of Atropine in Counteracting the Effect of Pituitrin and of Pilocarpine Injected into the Cerebral Ventricles (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 233, Reel 148)
      - IV. The Method of Action of Pituitrin Introduced into the Ventricle (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 234, Reel 148)
      - V. The Counteractive Effect of Tribomethanol (Avertin) on the Stimulatory Response to Pituitrin Injected in the Ventricle (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 235, Reel 148)
      - VI. Concerning a Possible "Parasympathetic Center" in the Diencephalon (294), 1931 (Box 185, Folder 236, Reel 148)
      - One Hundred and Fifty Years. From Tallow-dip to Television (295), 1931 (Box 186, Folder 237, Reel 149)
      - One Hundred and Fifty Years. From Tallow-dip to Television (295), 1931 (Box 186, Folder 238, Reel 149)
      - George Strong Derby (296), 1931 (Box 186, Folder 239, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 240, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 241, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 242, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 243, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 244, Reel 149)
      - Peptic Ulcers and the Interbrain (301), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 245, Reel 149)
      - Further Concerning a Parasympathetic Center in the Interbrain (VII-VIII) (302), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 246, Reel 149)
      - Report of the Surgeon-in-Chief (304), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 247, Reel 149)
      - The Specific Dynamic Action of Protein in Patients with Pituitary Disease (305), 1932 (Box 186, Folder 248, Reel 149)
      - Concerning a Hypothalamic Center for Parasympathetic Impulses (306), 1933 (Box 186, Folder 249, Reel 149)
      - "Dyspituitarism": Twenty Years Later (307), 1933 (Box 186, Folder 250, Reel 149)
      - "Dyspituitarism": Twenty Years Later (307), 1933 (Box 186, Folder 251, Reel 149)
      - "Dyspituitarism": Twenty Years Later (307), 1933 (Box 187, Folder 252, Reel 149)
      - Medicine at the Crossroads (309), 1933 (Box 187, Folder 253, Reel 149)
      - Medicine at the Crossroads (309), 1933 (Box 187, Folder 254, Reel 150)
      - William Thomas Councilman (310), 1933 (Box 187, Folder 255, Reel 150)
      - In Honor of Professor Elihu Thomson (311), 1933 (Box 187, Folder 256, Reel 150)
      - Experimental Pituitary Basophilism (314), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 257, Reel 150)
      - Experimental Pituitary Basophilism (314), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 258, Reel 150)
      - The Doctors Welch of Norfolk (315), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 259, Reel 150)
      - The Pioneer Medical Schools of Central New York (316), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 260, Reel 150)
      - The Pioneer Medical Schools of Central New York (316), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 261, Reel 150)
      - The Pioneer Medical Schools of Central New York (316), 1934 (Box 187, Folder 262, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) I. The Harvard Unit and the Ambulance Américaine, 1934 (Box 187, Folder 263, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) I. The Harvard Unit and the Ambulance Américaine, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 264, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) II. The Battle of Boston Common, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 265, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) II. The Battle of Boston Common, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 266, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) III. With the B. E. F. in France, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 267, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) III. With the B. E. F. in France, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 268, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) IV. With the A. E. F., 1934 (Box 188, Folder 269, Reel 150)
      - From a Surgeon's Journal (317) Unidentified, 1934 (Box 188, Folder 270, Reel 151)
      - Psychiatrists, Neurologists, and the Neurosurgeon (318), 1935 (Box 188, Folder 271, Reel 151)
      - The Humanizing of Science (319), 1935 (Box 188, Folder 272, Reel 151)
      - The Humanizing of Science (319), 1935 (Box 188, Folder 273, Reel 151)
      - The Humanizing of Science (319), 1935 (Box 188, Folder 274, Reel 151)
      - William Beaumont's Rendezvous with Fame (320), 1935 (Box 188, Folder 275, Reel 151)
      - Ivan Pavlov (321), 1936 (Box 189, Folder 276, Reel 151)
      - Prefatory Note to: The Ultimate Results of Operations for Intracranial Tumors (322), 1936 (Box 189, Folder 277, Reel 151)
      - A Bibliographical Study of the Galvani and the Aldini Writings on Animal Electricity (323), 1936 (Box 189, Folder 278, Reel 151)
      - Corrigenda and Addenda to The Life of Sir William Osler (324), 1936 (Box 189, Folder 279, Reel 151)
      - Corrigenda and Addenda to The Life of Sir William Osler (324), 1936 (Box 189, Folder 280, Reel 151)
      - Ercole Lelli and His Écorché (325), 1937 (Box 189, Folder 281, Reel 151)
      - Ercole Lelli and His Écorché (325), 1937 (Box 189, Folder 282, Reel 151)
      - Perry Williams Harvey (326), 1937 (Box 189, Folder 283, Reel 151)
      - Remarks at Alumni Luncheon (328), 1937 (Box 189, Folder 284, Reel 151)
      - Toast Given at Luncheon, Association for Research in Nervous and Mental Disease, New York, 27 December, 1937 (329) (Box 189, Folder 285, Reel 152)
      - The Mayo Brothers and Their Clinic, Science Magazine, 1939 (Box 189, Folder 286, Reel 152)
    - Papers from Dr. Cushing's Clinics and Laboratories
      - Davidoff, L. M.; Studies in Acromegaly II, Historical Note (418), 1926 (Box 189, Folder 287, Reel 152)
      - Davidoff, L. M.; Studies in Acromegaly III, The Anamnesis and Symptomatology in One Hundred Cases (419), 1926 (Box 189, Folder 288, Reel 152)
    - Unpublished
      - Maryland Association of Yale Alumni, Circa 1909 (Box 190, Folder 289, Reel 152)
      - Resuscitation by liberation of the medulla after prolonged artificial respiration during operations for cerebellar tumor, Circa 1912 (Box 190, Folder 290, Reel 152)
      - American Neurological Association: lecture, 1919 (Box 190, Folder 291, Reel 152)
      - Surgical Section, American Medical Association: lecture, 1919 (Box 190, Folder 292, Reel 152)
      - American College of Surgeons: address at conclusion of presidency, 1923 (Box 190, Folder 293, Reel 152)
      - Anniversary of the birth of Dr. Welch, 1933 (Box 190, Folder 294, Reel 152)
      - Letter for students' class book, 1926 (Box 190, Folder 295, Reel 152)
      - Further concerning the acoustic neuromas: lecture, 1926 (Box 190, Folder 296, Reel 152)
      - Society of Clinical Surgery, 1926 (Box 190, Folder 297, Reel 152)
      - Wyllys Taylor birthday address, 1926 (Box 190, Folder 298, Reel 152)
      - Surgical Clinic - University of Kochester Scientific Medical Conference, 1926 October 26 (Box 190, Folder 299, Reel 152)
      - Unveiling of the Nathan Smith plaque, 1928-1929
        See: Series I, folder 420
      - Studies in acromegaly: preparatory note, Circa 1929 (Box 190, Folder 299a, Reel 152)
      - Edwin Smith-Papyrus, 1931 (Box 190, Folder 300, Reel 152)
      - Retirement from the ______ Club, 1932 (Box 190, Folder 301, Reel 152)
      - Dr. Mendell's ______, [1933?] (Box 190, Folder 302, Reel 152)
      - National Institute of Social Sciences: address, 1935 (Box 190, Folder 303, Reel 152)
      - The anterior pituitary body: lecture, 1935 (Box 190, Folder 304, Reel 152)
      - Alpha Omega Alpha: address, 1938 (Box 190, Folder 305, Reel 152)
      - Touching for the Evil: presidential address given before the Elizabethan Club, 1939 May 22 (Box 190, Folder 306, Reel 152)
      - Touching for the Evil: presidential address given before the Elizabethan Club, 1939 May 22 (Box 190, Folder 307, Reel 152)
      - Endocrines and growth: lecture (Box 190, Folder 308, Reel 152)
      - Letter to the editor, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 309, Reel 152)
      - Ingersoll, J. W. D.: memoir, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 310, Reel 152)
      - Veterinary medicine, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 311, Reel 152)
      - Operations for tumors invading the cerebellum, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 312, Reel 152)
      - A case of pituitary tumor with exophthalmic goitre, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 313, Reel 152)
      - Experimentation on human beings, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 314, Reel 152)
      - James Gregory Mumford, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 315, Reel 152)
      - Anatomy of the circle of willis, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 316, Reel 152)
      - Tumors arising from the IV ventricle areae postremae, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 317, Reel 152)
      - Lean versus fat types of dyspituitarism: lecture, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 318, Reel 152)
      - Abstracts of cases, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 319, Reel 152)
      - Herbals and bestiaries (Box 190, Folder 320, Reel 152)
      - Technique of laminectomy, n. d. (Box 190, Folder 321, Reel 152)
    - Clinic and research notes
      - Abscess of the temporal lobe treated by marsupialization, 1921 (Box 191, Folder 322, Reel 153)
      - Anaesthesia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 323, Reel 153)
      - Astereognosis, 1923-1926 (Box 191, Folder 324, Reel 153)
      - Basilar aneurysms, 1922 (Box 191, Folder 325, Reel 153)
      - Blood vessels, 1923, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 326, Reel 153)
      - Bone disease, 1910-1927 (Box 191, Folder 327, Reel 153)
      - Brain, 1925-1926 (Box 191, Folder 328, Reel 153)
      - Brain tumors, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 329, Reel 153)
      - Cerebellar tubercules, 1919, 1927 (Box 191, Folder 330, Reel 153)
      - Cerebro-spinal fluid, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 331, Reel 153)
      - Choroid plexus, 1926 (Box 191, Folder 332, Reel 153)
      - Cortical topography, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 333, Reel 153)
      - Diabetes insipidus, 1909-1926 (Box 191, Folder 334, Reel 153)
      - Dyspituitarism, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 335, Reel 153)
      - Ear, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 336, Reel 153)
      - Endocrine disorders (Box 191, Folder 337, Reel 153)
      - Exophthalamus with brain tumors, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 338, Reel 153)
      - False localizing signs in brain tumor-trigeminal anaesthesia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 339, Reel 153)
      - Focal epilepsy, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 340, Reel 153)
      - Frölich's syndrome from adenoma and from Rathke's pouch tumor, 1925 (Box 191, Folder 341, Reel 153)
      - Gastro-urinary surgery-anomalies, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 342, Reel 153)
      - Gunshot wounds (Box 191, Folder 343, Reel 153)
      - Hemianopsia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 344, Reel 153)
      - Hemianopsia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 345, Reel 153)
      - Hemianopsia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 346, Reel 153)
      - Hemianopsia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 347, Reel 153)
      - Hemianopsia with frontal lobe lesions, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 348, Reel 153)
      - Hernia and abdominal wall, 1925 (Box 191, Folder 349, Reel 153)
      - Homonymous hemianopsia, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 350, Reel 153)
      - Intracranial aneurysm, 1925-1929, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 351, Reel 153)
      - Intracranial metastases, n. d. (Box 191, Folder 352, Reel 153)
      - Joints and bursae (Box 191, Folder 353, Reel 153)
      - The mixed syndrome (overgrowth, adiposity, and sexual dystrophy) (Box 192, Folder 354, Reel 153)
      - Neuralgia of the neuro facialis, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 355, Reel 153)
      - Neurotrophic neuroses, 1914-1919 (Box 192, Folder 356, Reel 153)
      - Occipito-altoid operations, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 357, Reel 153)
      - Operative surgery, 1905, 1908 (Box 192, Folder 358, Reel 153)
      - Pigmentation, 1916, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 359, Reel 153)
      - Pituitary-illustrations, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 360, Reel 153)
      - Pituitary adenomas, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 361, Reel 153)
      - Pituitary tumor and choked disk, 1921, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 362, Reel 153)
      - Plastic surgery, 1919 (Box 192, Folder 363, Reel 153)
      - Recklinghausen's disease, 1917-1926, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 364, Reel 153)
      - Resection of gut of dogs, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 365, Reel 153)
      - Resuscitation cases, 1919 (Box 192, Folder 366, Reel 153)
      - Splenectomy, 1920 (Box 192, Folder 367, Reel 153)
      - Spina bifida-hydrocephaly, 1920, 1924-1925 (Box 192, Folder 368, Reel 153)
      - Stomach and duodemun (Box 192, Folder 369, Reel 153)
      - Surgery of peripheral nerves, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 370, Reel 153)
      - Surgical disorders of the brain, 1927 (Box 192, Folder 371, Reel 153)
      - Temporal lobe abcess, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 372, Reel 153)
      - Third year surgical clinics, 1923-1924 (Box 192, Folder 373, Reel 153)
      - Thyroid, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 374, Reel 153)
      - Transphenoidal cases and their end results, 1920 (Box 192, Folder 375, Reel 153)
      - Trigeminal neuralgia, 1919 (Box 192, Folder 376, Reel 153)
      - Tuberculoma, n. d. (Box 192, Folder 377, Reel 153)
      - Various diseases and tumors (Box 192, Folder 378, Reel 153)
      - Unidentified and fragments (Box 192, Folder 379, Reel 153)
  - Family Papers, 1745-1940; Series IV; 3.25 linear feet (8 boxes, 4 reels)
    This series is composed of papers, including correspondence, financial records, writings, diaries, photographs, and memorabilia, which reflect the lives of four generations of Cushing family members. The series includes no professional material either written by or addressed to Harvey Cushing. Correspondence exchanged between family members and Harvey Cushing is in Series I.
    The papers are organized according to the family member who either created them or held them as part of their personal papers. Files are arranged alphabetically by the names of these family members. The lives of family members in Massachusetts and Ohio are documented in these files as is the practice of medicine throughout the nineteenth century.
    The series begins with a few folders of material relating to the Cushing family in general. These are followed by genealogical tables of the Cushing family, which were Harvey Cushing for his children.
    Files for Betsey Maria Williams Cushing and Henry Kirke Cushing are among the largest in the series. These contain an exchange of letters between husband and wife during the Civil War, as well as diaries of Henry Kirke Cushing. The series also includes several folders of correspondence belonging to Katherine Crowell Cushing. The oldest materials in the series are financial accounts of David and John Cushing, which date from the late eighteenth century.
    - General
      - Photographs, 1908, undated (Box 193, Folder 1, Reel 154)
      - Cleveland Academy, 1875, 1876, undated (Box 193, Folder 2, Reel 154)
    - Genealogy
      - Ancestral tables for Henry Kirke Cushing, undated (Box 193, Folder 3, Reel 154)
      - Ancestral tables for Henry Kirke Cushing: loose material found in volume, 1903, 1912 (Box 193, Folder 4, Reel 154)
      - Ancestral tables "Junior Book", undated (Box 193, Folder 5, Reel 154)
      - Ancestral tables "Junior Book": loose material found in volume, 1878-1924, undated (Box 193, Folder 6, Reel 154)
      - Ancestral tables "Senior Book", undated (Box 193, Folder 7, Reel 154)
      - Ancestral tables "Senior Book": loose material found in volume, 1882-1897 (Box 193, Folder 8, Reel 154)
      - Miscellaneous, 1923, 1937, undated (Box 193, Folder 9, Reel 154)
    - Cushing, Betsey Maria Williams
      - Correspondence, 1858-1861 June 16 (Box 193, Folder 10, Reel 154)
      - Correspondence, 1861 June 19-July 21 (Box 193, Folder 11, Reel 154)
      - Correspondence, 1861 July 23-1897 (Box 193, Folder 12, Reel 154)
      - Book of accounts of her share of the estate of her late grandfather, Zalmon Fitch, 1861-1873 (Box 193, Folder 13, Reel 154)
      - Book of accounts of her share of the estate of her late grandfather, Zalmon Fitch: loose material found in volume, 1861-1873 (Box 193, Folder 14, Reel 154)
      - Betsey Maria Williams [Cushing] and her Forebears, 1839-1921, undated (Box 194, Folder 15, Reel 154)
      - Betsey Maria Williams [Cushing] and her Forebears: loose material found in volume, 1903, 1936, undated (Box 194, Folder 16, Reel 154)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 194, Folder 17, Reel 154)
    - Cushing, Cornelia Briggs
      - Correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia, 1835-1856 (Box 194, Folder 18, Reel 154)
      - Correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia: loose material found in volume, 1849-1856, undated (Box 195, Folder 19, Reel 155)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1861, 1878 (Box 195, Folder 20, Reel 155)
    - Cushing, David
      - Daybook, 1795-1809 (Box 195, Folder 21, Reel 155)
      - Daybook: loose material found in volume, 1795-1809 (Box 195, Folder 22, Reel 155)
    - Cushing E. F.
      - "Precision in the Treatment of Whooping Cough", 1909 (Box 195, Folder 23, Reel 155)
      - Memorabilia, 1897-1923 (Box 195, Folder 24, Reel 155)
    - Cushing, Erastus
      - Correspondence, 1856-1857 (Box 195, Folder 25, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1867-1870 (Box 195, Folder 26, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1872-1879, undated (Box 195, Folder 27, Reel 155)
      - Diaries, 1874 (Box 195, Folder 28, Reel 155)
      - Diaries, 1898-1899 (Box 195, Folder 29, Reel 155)
      - Thesis, Berkshire Medical School, 1824 (Box 195, Folder 30, Reel 155)
      - Writings, unidentified, undated (Box 195, Folder 31, Reel 155)
      - "Erastus Cushing, Mary Ann Platt and their forebears", 1745-1910 (Box 196, Folder 32, Reel 155)
      - "Erastus Cushing, Mary Ann Platt and their forebears": loose material found in volume, 1745-1910 (Box 196, Folder 33, Reel 155)
    - Cushing, Henry Kirke
      - Correspondence, 1854-1858 (Box 196, Folder 34, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1861 May (Box 196, Folder 35, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1861 June 2-16 (Box 196, Folder 36, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1861 June 20-July 9 (Box 196, Folder 37, Reel 155)
      - Correspondence, 1861 July 11-28 (Box 196, Folder 38, Reel 156)
      - Correspondence, 1861 August-September (Box 196, Folder 39, Reel 156)
      - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 196, Folder 40, Reel 156)
      - Correspondence, 1894, 1897-1898 (Box 196, Folder 41, Reel 156)
      - Correspondence, 1903-1909 (Box 196, Folder 42, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1861 (Box 196, Folder 43, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1900, 1902 (Box 196, Folder 44, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1903 (Box 196, Folder 45, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1905, 1906 (Box 197, Folder 46, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1907, 1908 (Box 197, Folder 47, Reel 156)
      - Diaries, 1909, 1910 (Box 197, Folder 48, Reel 156)
      - "Memorabilia of Henry Kirke Cushing", 1827-1910 (Box 197, Folder 49, Reel 157)
      - Notes, 1855 (Box 197, Folder 50, Reel 157)
      - Scrapbook, 1857-1865 (Box 198, Folder 51, Reel 157)
      - Miscellany, 1891, 1910, undated (Box 198, Folder 52, Reel 157)
    - Cushing, John and Olive
      - Financial records, 1787-1813 (Box 198, Folder 53, Reel 157)
      - Financial records, 1814-1842, undated (Box 198, Folder 54, Reel 157)
    - Cushing, Katherine Crowell
      - Correspondence, 1897-1905 July (Box 198, Folder 55, Reel 157)